<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Schlessinger</title>
    <description>Med Student | Programmer | Yoga Instructor</description>
    <link>http://www.danielschlessinger.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.danielschlessinger.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>On becoming, and staying, a world-class beginner: DBC culture lessons from Shereef</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago when I told someone that I teach yoga, they asked, &amp;quot;So does that mean you know how to do every pose now?&amp;quot; I politely explained that, no, I don&amp;#39;t know all of them, but that I&amp;#39;ve become much more confident and knowledgeable through the teacher training process. But when I decided they were ready to listen on a deeper level, I told them that I never want to be anything but a beginner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I resonated with &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/85001014/&quot;&gt;Shereef&amp;#39;s fireside chat&lt;/a&gt; in many ways, but this one came to mind first. It&amp;#39;s his second point, when he&amp;#39;s talking about everyone&amp;#39;s fears coming into Dev Bootcamp. Some people are scared they&amp;#39;re going to be left behind, and nervously see the people in their cohort who seem lightyears ahead. Others think the rest of the group is just too slow for them. In reality, we&amp;#39;re not as far apart as we all think: &lt;strong&gt;we&amp;#39;re just beginners.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a yoga teacher, it didn&amp;#39;t surprise me when Shereef said that the DBC instructors often feel the same way. We&amp;#39;re all learning. According to Shereef, if we can enter DBC with the &amp;quot;kitchen&amp;quot; attitude, we might grow into world-class beginners. How refreshing! I feel much more secure going into a program that 1) acknowledges its practical limits (of how much someone can learn in an 18-week time span) and 2) constantly stretches those limits, and 3) welcomes students to stretch the limits as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if yoga practitioners took the same attitude. Maybe that&amp;#39;s why no one wants to sign up for a basic class once they&amp;#39;ve taken the power option. Everyone is a beginner. Relish it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.danielschlessinger.com/DBC-Cultural-Week-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.danielschlessinger.com/DBC-Cultural-Week-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>