<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Schlessinger</title>
    <description>Med Student | Programmer | Yoga Instructor</description>
    <link>http://www.danielschlessinger.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.danielschlessinger.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Dbc Cultural Week 1</title>
        <description>&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../index.html#blog&quot;&gt;Cultural Blog&lt;/a&gt;: Week 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;On becoming, and staying, a world-class beginner: DBC culture lessons from Shereef&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;        &amp;lt;h3 class=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot;&amp;gt;_July 22, 2014_
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;        &amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/85001014&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;371&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago when I told someone that I teach yoga, they asked, &amp;quot;So does that mean you know how to do every pose now?&amp;quot; I politely explained that, no, I don&amp;#39;t know all of them, but that I&amp;#39;ve become much more confident and knowledgeable through the teacher training process. But when I decided they were ready to listen on a deeper level, I told them that I never want to be anything but a beginner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I resonated with &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/85001014/&quot;&gt;Shereef&amp;#39;s fireside chat&lt;/a&gt; in many ways, but this one came to mind first. It&amp;#39;s his second point, when he&amp;#39;s talking about everyone&amp;#39;s fears coming into Dev Bootcamp. Some people are scared they&amp;#39;re going to be left behind, and nervously see the people in their cohort who seem lightyears ahead. Others think the rest of the group is just too slow for them. In reality, we&amp;#39;re not as far apart as we all think: &lt;strong&gt;we&amp;#39;re just beginners.&lt;/strong&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;As a yoga teacher, it didn&amp;#39;t surprise me when Shereef said that the DBC instructors often feel the same way. We&amp;#39;re all learning. According to Shereef, if we can enter DBC with the &amp;quot;kitchen&amp;quot; attitude, we might grow into world-class beginners. How refreshing! I feel much more secure going into a program that 1) acknowledges its practical limits (of how much someone can learn in an 18-week time span) and 2) constantly stretches those limits, and 3) welcomes students to stretch the limits as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if yoga practitioners took the same attitude. Maybe that&amp;#39;s why no one wants to sign up for a basic class once they&amp;#39;ve taken the power option. Everyone is a beginner. Relish it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.danielschlessinger.com/DBC-Cultural-Week-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.danielschlessinger.com/DBC-Cultural-Week-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Favorite Websites</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;#1: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;            [
                ![email](../images/NYT.png)
            ](http://www.nytimes.com/)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One website I read almost every day is the New York Times online. Not only are they an excellent source of news, but they also have managed to adapt to the wild changes that have plagued most other traditional media. I love the NYT infographics, which are informative, creative and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first look at their website, my eye is drawn to the name, like most newspapers or online media. From there, my eye travels down to look at the featured photo in the center, then to the top left article title, because of its distinct formatting. The website functionally draws the reader to various stories by presenting articles at various vertical heights. I believe the NYT website is elegant and easy on the eyes. It is bold, open, and discrete. The purpose is to inform the public, and the sense I get from the website matches that: clear, vivid, informative, serious, and trustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it very easy to browse this website. As a news junkie, I of course get lost in the articles and end up spending too much time on the site. I enjoy the way they link to other articles mildly but effectively – they present beautiful media and infographics from other stories midway through a related article. This is impactful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;#2: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/&quot;&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;            &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;imgs&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
                [
                    ![kick1](../images/kick1.png)](http://www.kickstarter.com/)
                [
                    ![kick2](../images/kick2.png)](http://www.kickstarter.com/)
            &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t use Kickstarter everyday, but when I do, it’s always a lovely experience. I enjoy the vision behind crowdsourcing and I’ve actually seen a few friends’ dreams come true because of their service. I’ve funded a few projects that I’ve enjoyed, and I imagine I’ll continue to use this site as it grows, and maybe I’ll even use it to fund a project of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I like the most about this site is the design. There aren’t too many websites I would call beautiful, but this is one of them. I love the green font color in the logo. I love the navigation, which is so simple – just “Discover” and “Start” yet so effective. The site is bright all around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these things fit with what I see as their overall vision. Of course the nav just has those two options – what else would you want to do with their site? Why bog you down with unnecessary, distracting words just because most other sites do? I think the site is spunky because of the colors and fun because of the navigation. It’s also always surprising because of the wonderful things you can find using the service. It’s innovative because it totally reworked what a fundraising site should look like and has spawned so many other similar concepts. And it’s joyful, because of all of these elements working together to leave people happier than when they started. It goes without saying that here, too, I lose many hours of my day, joyfully browsing other people’s dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;#3: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.songza.com/&quot;&gt;Songza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;            [
                ![email](../images/Songza.png)
            ](http://www.nytimes.com/)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I use Spotify to listen to music I know I like, I use Songza to find music I don’t know I like yet. It is a visually-appealing, smart, trustworthy music engine that can output music for seemingly any mood or genre. The music selection is also remarkable. I use this exclusively over Pandora now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visually, the site is incredibly user-friendly. Finding your music is intuitive because clicking on a genre, activity, or mood opens up a column to the right. It reminds me of the ability to view folders in columns on a Mac. I enjoy this, and it makes me want to stay on the site for longer. The site is colorful and bright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, then, I love using this site. In general, Songza is exciting, crisp, elegant, consistent, and useful. It is my go to music engine when playing music for friends. I think the visual appeal is strong and clear. The navigation is simple and intelligent. Naturally, we end up listening for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.danielschlessinger.com/DBC-Technical-Week-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.danielschlessinger.com/DBC-Technical-Week-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>